

Details

Plot 208a, Hakimi Aliyu Layout Mokwa, Niger State, 913104 Nigeria

+234(0)7052532663 orpaastephen@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Nigerian

18th October, 1996

Links

Portfolio

<u>LinkedIn</u>

Twitter Github

Skills

CCNA

Windows Server

Linux

Flutter

Java

C++

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Vue

Python

Joomla

Microsoft Office

Fast Learner

Profile

High-energy and dedicated IT Officer with accumulated experience assisting colleagues in analyzing and problem-solving technical issues with workable solutions. Forward-thinking and team-oriented with a proven history of thinking strategically and initiating action to meet deadlines. Recognized by management and colleagues as an individual who takes on challenges and new responsibilities, and gets things done right.

Employment History

Assistant IT Officer (Full-Time), Flour Mills of Nigeria (Golden Sugar Company, Sunti), Ja'agi, Mokwa, Niger State

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

- As an Assistant IT Officer I was involve providing technical support related to both hardware and software.
- · Carryout quarterly system backup using Veeam
- · Implement Cisco Security firewall on the Network
- Monitoring Network using Meraki dashboard and Ensuring smooth flow of internet on company Switches and Access points (Cisco Routers)
- · Report and resolve network down times with full speed
- Responsible for update/implementation of system security patch, enforcing OS upgrade and Staff training for new UI usage
- Help to ensure the safe and efficient running of a company's IT gadgets and provide user technical support/assistance.
- Ensured company's computer network is always running smoothly, efficiently and up-to-date.
- Responsible for writing reports, training staff on new technologies, and developing/implement contingency plans in case of network failure.
- Performed installations and configuring computer on FMN Domain and Networks
- · Setting Up Peripherals, Maintaining and Repairing them.
- and I analyzed several online job postings to identify these core duties and responsibilities to system end-users (staffs).

User Support (Intern), Federal University of Agriculture, Makurdi, Benue State

MARCH 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2013

Job Description

- Assist over 3,000 students in the creation of student's Username and password to grant them access to ICT wireless facility
- Enable Staff to collate student data consumption information from the school admin network server.
- Team leader of IT student during the PC upgrade from wired to wireless card to enable wireless networking in ICT hall.
- · Team leader for quarterly PC maintenance
- · Assist Student use the school portal efficiently.

Junior Android Developer (Intern), Build Space, Makurdi, Benue State

MARCH 2021 - DECEMBER 2022

- · Designed app using Flutter (Dart & Kotlin)
- Implement Apps Using Firebase, Google Cloud and Google authentication
- · Used Retrofit for handling RESTful AP calls
- Used Mobile-ads and Facebook

Effective Time Management

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Communication Skills

Ability to Multitask

Hobbies

Traveling and Reading

Languages

English

Hausa

Espanol

Hebrew

Computer Instructor (Full Time), Rock Computer Cyber Cafe, Makurdi, Benue State

NOVEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2021

- · Install and Administrate Mikrotic software over the wireless network
- · Configure/Setup wireless network firewall
- · Used e-Platform (Remita, Quickteller, Others) for payment

Store Keeper (Full Time), Saro Agro Science, Chiromawa, Kano State

APRIL 2015 - FEBRUARY 2018

- Monitor and ensure proper In-Flow and Out-Flow of Stocks ensure daily stock balancing with sales reps.
- Implemented new customer service strategies successfully, increasing customer satisfaction by 9% in 11 months.
- Calculate total payments received during a time period, and reconcile this with total sales.
- Used computerized systems that involve distributing and accounting for funds
- · Operate POS cash register, handling 20 transactions on average daily
- Calculate total payments received during a time period, and reconcile this with total sales.
- · Responsible for Quarterly Stock count

Security Personnel, Ashaka Security Company (ASCO), Sunti Golden Sugar, Ja'agi

APRIL 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

Computer Instructor, Bekesoft Infosys & Datatech, Mokwa, Niger State SEPTEMBER 2009 – JULY 2011

Job Description

- · Computer System Unit Assembly and Installation
- DBMS Application End-User
- · Ms-Office Application End-User
- · Corel-Draw & CS-4 End-User

Education

B.Sc Computer Science (in view), Federal University of Agriculture, Makurdi, Benue State

MARCH 2018 - NOVEMBER 2022

ND Computer Science, The Federal Polytechnic Bida , Niger State $\tt SEPTEMBER\ 2011-SEPTEMBER\ 2014$

SSCE, Government Day Secondary School, Kpege, Mokwa, Niger State

FSLC, Abi Nursery and Primary, Badariya, Brinin Kebbi, Kebbi State

Courses

Associate Android Developer, Google Developers

Mobile-Web Specialist, Google Developers

JULY 2021 - JULY 2024

Fundamentals of Android & iOS App using Flutter & Dart, London App Brewery + Google Developer

APRIL 2020

CCNA (Security), Network Bull, India

SEPTEMBER 2020

CCNA Associate (Networking), Network Bull, India

JULY 2014 - JULY 2018

CCNA Associate (Routing & Switching), Network Bull, India

OCTOBER 2014 - OCTOBER 2018

Diploma in Computer Operations, Bidapoly Consult

AUGUST 2012

References

References available upon request